Guide to the Edward A. Feigenbaum Papers SC0340
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Original accession, Accession ARCH-1986-052
  - Project files
    - Newell, Allen #3 Studies in Problem Solving: Subject 3 on the Crypt-Arithmetic Task (Donald + Gerrold = Robert). A. Newell, July 1967, C.I.T. reprint of "Limitations of the Current Stock of Ideas about Problem Solving" A. Newell Photocopy of "Heuristic Programming: Ill-Structured Problems" A. Newell "A Model for Functional Reasoning in Design." P. Freeman and A. Newell. "Some issues of representation in a general problem solver." George Ernst and A. Newell, Spring Joint Computer Conference, 1967. Photocopy of "Remarks on the Relationship Between Artificial Intelligence and Cognitive Psychology." A. Newell (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Nilsson, Nils J. Artificial Intelligence, Invited paper, IFIP Congress 74, by Nils J. Nilsson, Artificial Intelligence Center, SRI Artificial Intelligence--Research and Applications (progress report prepared for Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, May 1975) edited by Nils J. Nilsson by SRI project staff (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Paige, Jeffery M. "Cognitive Processes in Solving Algebra Word Problems" J.M. Paige and H.A. Simon, May 1965 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Papert, Seymour "Artificial Intelligence, Language, and the Study of Knowledge" by Ira Goldstein and S. Papert, from Cognitive Science #1 Draft of: The Artificial Intelligence of Hubert L. Dreyfuss: A Budget of Fallacies. S. Papert, Jan 1968 Revision of Section 1.0 Machines, Feb 1968, and copies of sections of previous paper. (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Panofsky, W. "Electrons Accelerated to the 10- to 20- Gev Range" W.K.H. Panofsky, R.B. Neal and the staff of the Stanford Linear Accelerator Center. Science, vol. 152, 3 June 1966 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Parker, Edwin B. Information and Society" (A Report to the National Commission on Libraries and Information Science) by Edwin B. Parker, (Prof.of Communication--Stanford) March, 1973 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Pask, Gordon #1 "Physical Analogues to the Growth of a Concept" G. Pask (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Pask, Gordon #3-8 "Some Comments on the Organization of Men, Machines and Concepts"--G. Pask, from Education for Information Science, 1965. "Teaching as a control-engineering process" G. Pask, originally appeared in Control, 1965. "Comments on the Cybernetics of Ethical, Sociological and Psychological Systems" G. Pask. Reprinted from Progress In Biocybernetics--Vol 3. 1966. "The Theory and Practice of Adaptive Teaching Systems." B.L. Lewis and G. Pask. Reprinted from Teaching Machines and Programmed Learning, II: Data and Directions, ed. Robert Glaser. "Man/Machine Interactin in Adaptively Controlled Experimental Conditions" G. Pask, Reprinted from Bulletin of Mathematical Biophysics, vol. 27, 1965, special issue. A Cybernetic Model for some Types of Learnng and Mentation. G. Pask. Manuscript of invited paper for Bionics Symposium, Dayton, Ohio 1966. (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Pask, Gordon #9 Extract: "The cybernetics of evolutionary processes and of self organizing systems" for 3rd International Congress on Cybernetics, 1961. Intelligent Learning--G. Pask, 1966. (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Patrick, Robert L. Computers and Information Flow" by R. Patrick. University of California, School of Business Adm., BA 198A--Directed Group Study, Feigenbaum. Class work, Fall 1963 "Contracting for Computer Services" R. Patrick, Datamation, Feb. 1962 Wordbook of Computer Programming Terms, R. Patrick, March 1964. (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Pearl, Judea "Heuristic Information Processing: A Research Program in Computer Methodology" J. Pearl. For UCLA Computer Science Dept. Oct 1977. "An Interactive Program for Conversational Elicitation of Decision Structures" Antonio Leal and J. Pearl. IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man and Cybernetics, vol SMC-7 no. 5, May 1977. "On Summarizing Data Using Probalistic Assertions" by J. Pearl. IEEE Transactions of Information Theory, vol IT-23, No. 4, July 1977. (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Penfield, Wilder "The Interpretive Cortex" W. Penfield. Science, vol. 129, 26 June 1959. (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Perlis, Alan J. A Definition of Formula Algol by A. Perlis, R. Iturriaga, T.A. Standish. Presented at Symposium on Symbolic and Algebraic Manipulation, March 1966. (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Persson, Staffan Some Sequence Extrapolation Programs: A Study of Representation and Modeling in Inquiring Systems. S. Persson Sept 26, 1966. CS Dept, Stanford. (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Pfeiffer, John "Problems, Too, Have Problems" J. Pfeiffer. Fortune, Oct 196. "Checker Game of the Century" J. Pfeiffer. Popular Mechanics, Aug. 1964. (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Pohl, Ira--#1 "Heuristic Search Viewed as Path Finding in a Graph" I. Pohl; Artificial Intelligence 1 (1970). "Practical and Theoretical Considerations in Heuristic Search Algorithms" I. Pohl; (UC Santa Cruz, Information Sciences) Aug. 1975. Presented at NATO-ASI Conference on "The Machine Representations of Knowledge" July 1965. "Artificial Intelligence and Some Societal Implications" I. Pohl, March 1973. "Syntactic Models of Cognitive Behavior" I. Pohl, paper for NATO Symposium "Human Thinking - Computer Techniques for its Evaluation" Aug 1971. (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Pohl, Ira--#2 Bi-Directional and Heuristic Search In Path Problems, I. Pohl, SLAC Report, May 1969. "The avoidance of (relative) catastrophe, heuristic competence, genuine dynamic weighting and computational issues in heuristic problem solving." I. Pohl, March 1973. "A heuristic search program for the traveling salesman problem" I. Pohl and Patrick Banwell, July 1973. "Syntactic Models of Cognitive Behavior" I. Pohl, from Artificial and Human Thinking, 1973. (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - Polya, G. Intuitive Outline of the Solution of a Basic Combinatorial Problem" G. Polya, from Switching Theory in Space Technology, 1963. (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - Polyani, Michael "Experience and the Perception of Pattern" M. Polyani Chapter 11 from Modeling of Mind, July 18, 1963. (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - Postman, Leo Degree of Learning and Interserial Interference in Retention. L. Postman and D.A. Riley. 1959. "Short-Term Memory and Incidental Learning" L. Postman. (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - Pribram, Karl H. "A Review of Theory in Physiological Psychology" K.H. Pribram, reprinted from Annual Review of Psychology, vol. 11 1960. "A Progress Report in the Experimental Analysis of the Neurological Process Disturbed by Frontal Lesions in Primates," K. Pribram, A. Ahumada, J. Hartog, L. Roos July 1962. "The New Neurology: Memory, Novelty, Thought and Choice" K. Pribram, reprinted from EEG and Behavior, 1963. (Box 40, Folder 23)
    - Pylyshyn, Zenon W. #1 "Computational Models and Empirical Constraints," Z. Pylyshyn. Reprinted from The Behavioral and Brain Sciences (1978) I. "Minds, Machines and phenomenology: Some reflections on Dreyfus' 'What Computers Can't Do'" Z. Pylyshyn. Offprint from Cognition: International Journal of Cognitive Psychology. "What the Mind's Eye tells the Mind's Brain: A Critique of Mental Imagery," Z. Pylyshyn. From Psychological Bulletin, 1973, vol. 80, no. 1. "Computer Models of Language Conprehension" Z. Pylyshyn. "Competence and Psychological Reality," Z. Pylyshyn. American Psychologist, June 1972. (Box 40, Folder 24)
    - Munich Conference, 1961-62 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - NASA, memo, 1972 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - National Security Agency Seminar, 1976 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - NATO Symposium Aug. 1971 (ELITHORN), 1970-71 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - NCR (Norm de la Chapelle), letter, 1978 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Allen Newell Visit, 1966 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Norman Nie / Dale H. Bent, papers, 1966 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - NIH--Computer Research Study Section, 1968-71 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - NIH/Freedom of Information Act, 1976 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - NIH: Networks, 1972 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - NIH Study Section, 1972 Sep 20-22 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - NIH Proposal, 1970-72 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - NIH Trip--Spring, 1970 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - NIH Trip--Spring, 1972 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Nils Nilsson CV, 1977 (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - NOS: An Original Story, 1954 (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Influence in Small Group Problem Solving, 1956 (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - "An Experimental Course in Simulation of Cognitive Processes" by E. A. Feigenbaum, 1962 (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Generalization of an Elementary Perceiving and Memorizing Machine, circa 1962 (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - SCP Working Paper # 1: "Education for Research in Computer Simulation of Cognitive Processes" by E. A. Feigenbaum (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - SCP Working PAper # 3: "Recent Experiments with the EPAM Simulation of Verbal Learning" by E. A. Feigenbaum, 1961 (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - SCP Working Paper # 4: "Generalization of ëéan Elementary Perceiving and Memorizing Machine" by E. A. Feigenbaum, 1961 (Box 50, Folder 22)
    - SCP Working Paper # 8: "Generalization of an Elementary Perceiving and Memorizing Machine" by E. A. Feigenbaum, 1962 (Box 50, Folder 23)
    - SCP Working Paper # 17: "Memory Mechanisms and EPAM Theory: Monologue and Interchange at the First Conference on Remembering, Learning and Forgetting" by E. A. Feigenbaum, 1964 (Box 50, Folder 24)
    - "Elements of an Information Processing Theory of Memory" by E. A. Feigenbaum, 1964 (Box 50, Folder 25)
    - "Studies in Information Processing Theory: Similarity and Familiarity in Verbal Learning" by E. A. Feigenbaum and H. A. Simon [Rand Corp publication], 1964 (Box 50, Folder 26)
    - SCP Working Paper # 13: "Studies in Information Processing Theory: Similarity and Familiarity in Verbal Learning" by Herbert A. Simon and E. A. Feigenbaum, 1963 (Box 50, Folder 27)
    - Computer Simulation of Human Behavior by E. A. Feigenbaum, 1963 (Box 50, Folder 28)
    - "Performance of a Reading Task by an Elementary Perceiving and Memorizing Program" by E. A. Feigenbaum and H. A. Simon, 1961, 1963 (Box 50, Folder 29)
    - "Information Processing Theories of Learning: Summary of 1962-63 Activity" by E. A. Feigenbaum (Box 50, Folder 30)
    - Summaries and Abstracts: Research on an Information Processing Theory of Verbal Learning "Simulation of Human Verbal Learning Behavior" by E. A. ¯Feigenbaum and H. A. Simon, 1961-62 (Box 50, Folder 31)
    - "A Theory of the Serial Position Effect" by E. A. Feigenbaum and Herbert A. Simon, 1961 (Box 50, Folder 32)
    - Information Processing Language-V Manual, Second Edition, (2 copies), 1964 (Box 50, Folder 33)
    - "Artificial Intelligence Research" by E. A. Feigenbaum, Oct. 1963 in IEEE Transactions of the Professional Technical Group on Information, 1963-64 (Box 50, Folder 34)
    - "From Minsk to Pinsk Without Intourist"; Datamation, May 1965 (Box 50, Folder 35)
    - Soviet Computer Science Revisited, 1965 (Box 50, Folder 36)
    - "An Information Processing Theory of Verbal Learning" by E. A. Feigenbaum, 1959 (Box 50, Folder 37)
    - "Forgetting in an Association Memory" by E. A. Feigenbaum and H. A. Simon, 1961 (Box 50, Folder 38)
    - ESSEX/IPPRC, notebook, 1978 (Box 50, Folder 39)
    - ESSEX/IPPRC, correspondence and miscellany, 1978 (Box 50, Folder 40)
    - Hamburg conference, 1974 (Box 50, Folder 41)
    - IFIP conference, 1975 (Box 50, Folder 42)
    - Kiel [IPN conference], 1975 (Box 50, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence: Weizenbaum, Joe to Feigenbaum, 23 December 1970 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Preliminary report to DARPA, 9 November 1973 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Printout: EPAM II, code LIPLV, 1961 (1 of 3) (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Printout: EPAM II, code LIPLV, 1961 (2 of 3) (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Printout: EPAM II, code LIPLV, 1961 (3 of 3) (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Printout: EPAM III, listing in IPLV, 1963 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - EPAM DEC Tape for use on PDP 1/4/6/7 (noted as a backup) 1967 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - EPAM DEC Tape Backup (LISP) Wilber (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - [glass] of EPAM to Accompany Lectures (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Trip files
    - Articles About Russian Developments by Americans (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Dr. E. I. Arin (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Yershov Trip, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Yershov Trip, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Talks on Soviet Cybernetics Trip, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Russian Article in Communications of the Association for Computer Machinery, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Russian Addresses (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Soviet Reports (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Comments and Letters about Soviet Developments by Americans (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Soviet Technical Publications (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Notes for Trip to USSR, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Russian Language Exercises (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Letters to Russians (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Letters from Russians (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - IFAC Congress--Moscow (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Russian Visitors (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Feigenbaum Travel (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Russian Language Pamphlets (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Novak (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Travel---Rutgers, Carnegie-Mellon, July 5-14, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Hawaii Trip, May 1977 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Bob Lindsay--Expense Report (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Seminar/Berkeley Ext., Dec. 2, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - H and S Travel Funds (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - ACM, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - IJCAI IV--Russia (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - USA-Japan Computer Conference, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - National Computer Conference, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - ACM--San Diego, 1974 Nov (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - NATO Institute, August 1974 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - IFIPS Stockholm, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - International Congress of Administrative Sciences, Mexico DF (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Canberra Trip, May 6-10, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - National Computer Conference--ACM, May 1974 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - 6th Annual Computer Forum Meeting--Stanford, ERL 237, February 7-8, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Hawaii Conference, Jan. 7-11, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - American Mathematical Society Summer Meeting, August 1973 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - USA-Japan Computer Conference, October 1972 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - M17, Edinburgh, June 1972 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - France Trip (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - European Trip, Aug.-Sept. 1971 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - ARPA Contractors Meeting [found empty 9/10/2008], February 1971 (Box 10, Folder 44)
- Additional material, Accession ARCH-1991-030
  - Audiovisual materials
    - Ed Feigenbaum EE000 [HPP/KSL Outtakes], Video reel (Box 1)
    - HPP, Tom and Wah Ho, Barbara/students [HPP/KSL Outtakes], Video reel (Box 1)
    - HPP, Bruce/students, BG000, sig lunch, BB000 [HPP/KSL Outtakes], Video reel (Box 1)
    - Harold HH5000, also find at tail: HB0837-0924 [HPP/KSL Outtakes], Video reel (Box 1)
    - Harold BR5000, BH5000 at computer II, HB8000 in office, CU Brown - computer room, MOS BLUE CHIP, MOS circuit board [HPP/KSL Outtakes], Video reel (Box 1)
    - Penny RR300, Penny at computer, Penny with expert, MOS expert system graph, Diagrams, "AGE" [HPP/KSL Outtakes], Video reel (Box 1)
    - Charlotte [HPP/KSL Outtakes], Video reel (Box 1)
    - Charlotte, Ext. Hospital, Clinic sign, Cowell, DD7000, Files, Dr. Lenny--computer [HPP/KSL Outtakes], Video reel (Box 1)
    - Ted AA000 [HPP/KSL Outtakes], Video reel (Box 1)
    - Ted, Larry--Christopher, Computer Demo, Christopher's Demo, Larry and Christopher GG4000 [HPP/KSL Outtakes], Video reel (Box 1)
    - Bruce and Mike--Daylight Walk--Sound--Heads [HPP/KSL Outtakes], Audio tape (Box 1)
    - USC/ICI 10th Anniversary Conference, Dr. Edward Feigenbaum, Stanford, May 20, 1982; Beta cassette (Box 2)
    - EAF Japanese TV appearances and other Japanese, August 1983; Beta cassette (Box 2)
    - CS 520 Session 10, Feigenbaum talk, 2 June 1987; Beta cassette (Box 2)
    - "H.P.P", Beta cassette (Box 2)
    - Computer Chronicles--BI, MacNeil-Lehrer/5 Generation, November 25, 1983; Beta cassette (Box 2)
    - Friday Background VI/14: 1. When things start to talk 2. Student unrest in South Korea 3. HDB cracks, 1986 Apr 4; Beta cassette (Box 2)
    - MacNeil-Lehrer AI; Merv Griffin appearance; CBS evening reports (4) computers; computer chronicles, 1983 Apr 22, undated; Beta cassette (Box 2)
    - EAP, TV interview, November 28, 1988; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
    - Business View, "Highlights and Bestsellers," [Japanese on box], November 1983; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Westinghouse, April 14, 1987; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Laurel Miller, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - TI (A.M.) 3 and 4, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - TI (P.M.) 5 and 6, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - TI--afternoon 7; TI--late afternoon 8, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Bruce Johnson 1 and 3, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Bruce Johnson 2 and 4, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Bob Flast 1 and 2, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Bob Flast 3 and 4, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Bob Flast, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - NAVISTAR 1 and 2, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - NAVISTAR 3 and 4, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - NAVISTAR 5, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - FMC I [1], 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - FMC 2, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - FMC 3, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Fujitsu and ICOT I, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - NEC, ETL, SONY, CANON II, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - KAJIMA CRIEPI, MKI, TOYOTA III, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Interview with Gordon Bell (first tape), 2 sides, March 28, 1987; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Gordon Bell (continued), March 28, 1987; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Kurtzweil Panel at Boston Computer Society. EAF is a panelist [tape labelled "POWERSHARING'], circa 1987; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Chuck Williams, Inference Corp., HPN interview, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - [label crossed out TDK D-90], 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - KIEV, World of money, Nov. 28, 1988; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Dr. Edward Feigenbaum, KCBS--Jan Hutchins, Feb. 9, 1989; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Cuthbert, The Rise of the Expert Company, Nov. 1, 1988; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - A Symposium to Honor Mina Rees, EAF talk, Jan. 6, 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - EAF: Computer Forum Keynote, "Working Smarter", Feb. 1988; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - EAF speech for SPL 56 Conference, 1983; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Study Results of First Wave of Expert Systems Applications to Business, 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - KGO News Talk Radio, May 31, 1983; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Feigenbaum Talk, Berne, Switzerland, 1980; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - EAF 56 Talk at DEC, 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - SPL Conference on 5th generation, 1983; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Smithsonian World #603: From Information to Wisdom?, 1991 Apr 17; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - Papers
    - "Weekly Post," ["Shukan Posuto," Japanese magazine], special New Year's Issue; Feigenbaum and Minsky featured, Jan. 1986 (Box 4)
    - DENDRAL proposal (Box 4)
    - DENDRAL proposal, May 1976 (Box 4)
    - NIH Computers and Chemistry Renewal Application, 1976 (Box 4)
    - NIH Computers and Chemistry Renewal Application, December 1973 (Box 4)
    - Formal Representation of Human Judgement, Kleinmuntz, ed.; includes Feigenbaum article and early DENDRAL paper (Box 4)
    - The Ion Generator, a Heuristic Program in Mass Spectrometry, A. B. Delfino, 1974 (Box 4)
    - DENDRAL EAF, Publications (2 binders) (Box 5)
    - Album (labelled National University of Singapore): Lee Kuan Yew Distinguished Professorship, March 23-29, 1986 (Box 5)
    - "Early AI in the World" material (Box 5)
    - "Computer Science at Stanford: The Impact of the First Ten Years," award certificate inside (Box 6)
    - Final Report: "The First Ten Years of Artifical Intelligence at Stanford,", July 1973 (Box 6)
    - "Recent Research in Artificial Intelligence, Heuristic Programming, and Network Protocols,", July 1974 (Box 6)
    - SUMEX Renewal, 1985 (Box 6)
    - "Beyond Heuristic DENDRAL" (Box 6)
    - "Panel: History of Artificial Intelligence Research, 1956-61" Heuristic Programming Project Report No. HPP-77-42, 1977 (Box 6)
    - "Mechanization of Inductive Inference in Organic Chemistry," Stanford Artificial Intelligence Memo No. 54, Aug. 2, 1967 (Box 6)
    - "Applications of Artificial Intelligence for Chemical Inference. III. Aliphatic Ethers Diagnosed by Their Low-Resolution Mass Spectra and Nuclear Magnetic Resonance Data," from the Journal of the American Chemical Society, 91:25, Dec. 17, 1969 (Box 6)
    - E. F. Hutton Artificial Intelligence Forum--Edward A. Feigenbaum, coauthor, "The Fifith Generation" (Box 6)
    - Page proofs of Applications of Artifical Intelligence for Organic Chemistry: The DENDRAL Project (Box 6)
    - Copyright for Applications of Artifical Intelligence for Organic Chemistry (Box 6)
    - ESI--June 1985: Edward Feigenbaum on Fifth Generation Computer Systems and Artificial Intelligence: The Japanese, American and European Initiatives (Box 6)
    - Documentation from DENDRAL project (Box 6)
    - DENDRAL 29 [computer printout] (Box 7)
    - DENDRAL Project (Edward Feigenbaum, Joshua Lederberg) [printout] (Box 7)
    - "General Description of the Spectrum Predictor," B. Buchanan, Sept. 17, 1967 (Box 7)
    - "The Theory Behind a Computer Program for Predicting Mass Spectra of Organic Molecules," Bruce G. Buchanan, Nov. 9, 1967 (Box 7)
    - "DENDRAL's 0.1-order Theory of Mass Spectrometry," G. Gutherland and B. Buchanan, Dec. 12, 1967 (Box 7)
    - "Special Cases for the Predictor," Buchanan, Jan. 10, 1968 (Box 7)
    - "Using the Longest Chains Finding Program" (Box 7)
    - "Systematic Generation of Acyclic Structural Isomers,", Oct. 16, 1973 (Box 7)
    - DENDRAL Progress Report [printout], Oct. 11, 1973 (Box 7)
    - Molecular Ion Details (Box 7)
    - DENDRAL Historial I (Box 7)
    - DENDRAL Historial II (Box 7)
    - DENDRAL related materials [unlabelled black binder] (Box 7)
    - DENDRAL EAF, Cyclic Generator (Box 8)
    - Proceedings of the IEEE, includes article by Feigenbaum, Buchanan and Shortcliffe, Sept. 1979 (Box 8)
    - Fifth Illinois Conference on Medical Information Systems, includes article by Feigenbaum (Box 8)
    - National Academy of Engineering Directory of Members and Foreign Associates (Feigenbaum listed), July 1988 (Box 8)
    - AISB Quarterly, issue 40-41, Spring-Summer 1981 (Box 8)
    - IBM Almaden Research Center Brochure and letter concerning sabbatical program (Box 8)
    - Letters to Feigenbaum from Don and Jill Knuth, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous reprints, photocopied articles, and reports (Box 8)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1999-054
  - Report to the Linguistic Society of America by the Ad Hoc Committee to Study Natural Language Research Conducted, Funded or Used by the Department of Defense, 1985 Dec 27 (Box 1)
- Additional material, Accession ARCH-2005-101
  - Artificial Intelligence and Expert Systems
    - ACM Membership, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - AAAI--American Association for Artificial Inteligence, 1987--1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - American Association for Artificial Inteligence (AAAI)--Feigenbaum Presidency, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - American Association for Artificial Inteligence (AAAI), 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - American Association for Artificial Inteligence (AAAI) / M, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Artificial Intelligence (AI) / Entertainment Project, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - John Seeley Brown--National Academy of Engineering (NAE) nomination, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Contacts--ACMI, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - B. Grose, National Academy of Engineering (NAE), 1993 (Box 2, Folder 13)